

Simon Hoang 07928 669 888 simon.hoang23@gmail.com Manchester & London

United Kingdom

Portfolio
Behance
Dribbble
Instagram
LinkedIn

www.simonhoang.com
www.behance.net/simonhoang
www.dribbble.com/simonhoang23
www.instagram.com/uxdon
www.linkedin.com/in/simonhoang23

#### **ABOUT**

My role as a UXer centres around putting users at the core of product design, focusing on user experience as well as improving design practices and consistency. I concentrate on creating an appealing product that users want to engage with, through strong attention to detail, pushing boundaries with visuals and integrating modern frames of reference to convey the brand.

Through my experience, I have learnt the significance of user experience and user interface to guide the aesthetics of design, and the overall impact UX have on shaping a product.

I am passionate about user-centred design, and the impact it can have on people's lives. Above all else, I want to make a difference in the world, a real, quantifiable impact.

### **EXPERIENCE**

- Costa Coffee April 2021 to Present Senior Experience Designer
  - Responsible for leading the design of end-to-end product experiences to deliver value to customers and the business
  - Design, test and create user experiences across digital products (app and web) by taking a brief for a new journey or UX on the app or website and design, prototype and testing the journey
  - Driving consistency and continuity of user experiences across all digital channels regardless of IT solution (local or global)
  - Design best in class, consumer centric digital experiences globally for Costa
  - Apply a global lens to digital experiences to ensure they scale in international markets
  - Apply a 'mobile first' approach to user experience design, catering for our top used channels and devices
  - Create engaging concepts and prototypes that can be shared with markets that generate excitement
  - Work collaboratively with the Brand and Platform teams to create true omni-channel (offline and online) experiences
  - Create regular audits and analysis of competitor and industry leading experiences to share with stakeholders
  - Application of user-centric design techniques to create products that achieve customer and business goals
  - Applying a range of human-centred design methods to solve complex problems and facilitating crossfunctional teams to design new and optimise existing products
  - Effectively collaborate to engage customers and understanding the customer problem that is most valuable to solve
  - Data driven to incorporate the right balance of qualitative and quantitative insight into decision making, demonstrating the impact of the solution on business outcomes and use data to guide design decisions
  - Contributing to the principles, UX best practice and frameworks to help support the team to deliver a
    coherent experience at every touch point with Costa
  - Run and lead design workshops such as problem framing, design sprints
- cinch January 2020 to April 2021 Senior UX Designer
- TickX April 2019 to January 2020
  Lead UX/UI Designer
- TickX April 2018 to April 2019
  Senior UX/UI Designer
- Talent Works International July 2017 to April 2018
  UX/UI Designer
- UK Point Of Sale October 2015 to July 2017
   Senior Web Designer
- MBi Group January 2015 to October 2015
  Senior Creative
- **Elior -** December 2013 to January 2015 Digital Designer
- McDonald's Restaurants Ltd (Head Office) June 2010 to December 2013

  Designer
- Plus-Two January 2011, 1 day Graphic Designer (internship)
- X Artwork 1st July 2008 to 5th July 2008
   Graphic Designer (internship)
- D21 Mediaworks May 2008 to July 2008 Graphic Designer (internship)

## **DESIGN SKILLS**

Tools		Knowledge	
Figma	Confluence	UX/UI design	A/B testing
Adobe XD	Jira Software	Wireframing	Workshops
Sketch	Slack	User-centered design	Web Accessibility
Adobe Target	Trello	Grid and layout	Data analytics
Adobe Photoshop	UserTesting	White space	UX research
Adobe Illustrator	Maze	Low/high prototyping	Design system
Miro	Useberry	Typography	Design Sprint
InVision	Hotjar	HTML/CSS	Mobile UX design
Zeplin	Google Analytics	Colour theory	Usability testing

### RECOGNITION & FEATURED

Projects featured on Adobe Behance www.behance.net/simonhoang

Coding & Design Sprint articles featured on UX Collective - Medium online publishing https://simonhoang23.medium.com/

User Research article featured on The Startup - Medium online publishing https://simonhoang23.medium.com/

**Usability Testing article featured on Bootcamp - Medium online publishing** https://simonhoang23.medium.com/

Keynote Speaker at the UX Crunch event https://www.meetup.com/The-UX-Crunch-Manchester/events/259269010/

# EDUCATION

- BA (Hons) Degree and Higher National Diploma 2006 to 2010 Graphic Design University Of Salford
- BTEC National Diploma Graphic Design 2004 to 2006 City College Manchester
- BTEC National Diploma Fine Art (Partial) 2003 to 2004 City College Manchester
- GNVQ Intermediate Art and Design 2002 to 2003
  Bury College
- 8 GCSE's 1997 to 2002 Plant Hill High School